CALER SMITH

calebsmth54@gmail.com /In/calebsmth54 github.com/calebsmth54 https://calebsmth54.github.io/

Personal Summary

I am a game programmer who has learned by jumping in head first: Tinkering with mods, learning new tech by making games and tackling problems outside my expertise. I really enjoy working across disciplines, especially with design, and assisting colleagues with technical problems.

SKILLS

Languages: C++ C# JavascriptTools: Visual Studio Perforce Jira

• Game Development: 3D Math Unreal Engine 4 Unity

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Game Programmer

Waden Kane Games Studio

2016 - 2017

Lead N Brimstone

Worked with artists and designers to implement core gameplay systems and hook-up assets for an Unreal Engine 3D side-scrolling shooter

- Programmed AI, animations, player movement, and weapon code in C++
- · Worked closely with artists to import assets and hook them up with animation state machines
- Worked with designers on Blueprint interface for core code
- Responsible for maintaining project Perforce repository

Turtle Boarden

Playtested undocumented bugs, missing level boundary volumes and provided general feedback

Web Developer/Designer

Self-Employed

2016 - present

Worked with clients developing small Wordpress sites, installing various software on servers and designing/developing a companion app for a board game

- Programmed custom Node server, setup a Mongodb database and developed a browser based client for a card-based board game companion
- Installed MEAN platform on an Ubuntu server
- Modified Wordpress template PHP, HTML and CSS to produce desired results for client

Personal Experience

Unity (2017): Participated in several game jam and created small prototype games

Unreal Engine 4 (2015 - Present): Created several small prototypes; Assisted new developers on forums

Web Games (2015): Learned HTML5 by developing small games with Phaser

Modding (2005 - 2010): Developed maps and modified code for Half-Life 2 modifications

Education

Arizona State University (2012 - 2016) 124 credits towards B.A.

Film (2012 - 2016): Focuses were screenwriting and film editing

Hacks for Humanity (Codeathon, 2015): Coded a self-therapy prototype using Javascript

ASU Film Internship (2014): Worked as a PA on the pre-production of a *Justice Served*

Hollywood Invades Tempe (2013): Helped organization prepare and run screenings with film industry professionals